Oh, my, Master! Hello there!
Hello! Another hot day, eh?
It sure is!
Maybe there'll be an evening squall.
Right. I'll just walk in it to rinse off!
Hey Master, how about a trim?
Well, let's see. It's pretty long now.
Wait, I just got it cut
the day before yesterday!
You're right, you did!
The festival's coming up soon.
Yeah. It'll be another
lively one this year, I bet.
There you go.
It's hot today, so here's an extra scoop.
Are you sure? Thanks for the trouble.
Oh, listen, you know that young girl
apprentice who you often bring here?
She came the other day with some friends.
She's such a cheerful,
sweet girl, isn't she?
That Akane!
Oh? I wonder who her master could be?
Right! I hear that this master of hers
is a big fan of ice cream!
Whoops, if I stand here chatting,
my ice cream will melt!
- See you around!
- Thank you very much!
I'm coming in!
Oh, Master!
I know how busy you are,
so thanks for stopping by!
It's nothing. I was taking a walk, anyway.
So how's the festival prep going?
Everything okay?
Yes, it's more or less locked down.
Year after year, you and your apprentices
give it a shot in the arm,
so we can expect a big crowd.
We really appreciate it!
Hey, come on.
We're looking forward to it, too.
Do you think your apprentices
will be able to join us again?
Yes. Same as last year.
Maikeru, Koguma, Kyoji, Guriko.
The Mismatched Four!
I'm leaving them in your hands!
Wow, we'd appreciate that!
And next year, I think
we'll be getting one more little rebel.
- Oh?
- Really? A new apprentice, then?
What's their name?
We haven't decided on a stage name yet.
Since the apprenticeship
is a little ways off.
Well, that's something to look forward to!
You choose your apprentice's
stage name, right?
How do you come up with them?
Whatever hits me on a whim.
If there's anything I can help with,
let me know anytime.
- Okay, see you.
- Take care!
Her name, huh?
TWELFTH STORY
GRADUATION
Oh, so you won that Rakugo tournament?
Wow, lukewarm reaction!
Is that all you've got?
What? You won? Congrats!
- Something like that.
- Nope, sorry.
I mean, I always thought
you were gonna win.
Anyway...
This is for Dad!
I was more worried that you might
snap and cause a huge uproar.
Just who do you think I am?
Well, for what he did to you guys,
an outburst like that
would've been warranted.
Still, what good would that do?
If I can't convince him with my art,
there's no point.
Yeah?
Why are you snickering like that?
No reason!
It just hit me that
you've made the transition
from a Rakugoka's daughter
to a Rakugoka yourself.
Oh, yeah?
Cool thing to say for you, Jumbo.
What do you mean, "for you"?
All right, I'm out of here.
You better go tell the principal
in person that you won.
- Right! Take care!
- Sure.
Akane!
Lisa?
Yuka, too? What's going on?
Take a look at this! This!
What is this?
The teen girl Rakugo prodigy
who blew Issho Arakawa away.
With artistry of such unfathomable
maturity, given her youth,
she captivated not only the audience,
but also the panel of judges,
led by the very best of this era,
Issho Arakawa.
Well, well, people sure have
a thing for the youngsters!
Look at them, so exhilarated
over an amateur girl.
RYU'UN KENPUTEI
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Please don't take that the wrong way.
Master Shiguma.
There's no reason why I would be offended.
Is that right?
But this girl...
She's your apprentice, isn't she?
Her narrative style is exactly like yours.
Or maybe I should say...
So "Arakawa" strikes again?
SHOMEI TSUBAKIYA
I have nothing against him thriving,
but Master Issho has an arrogant attitude,
like he's the one carrying
the Rakugo industry on his shoulders.
Not to mention his school's
arbitrary standards for promotion
such as elevating someone to Futatsume
only two years into his apprenticeship.
He can't just do as he sees fit, or we--
I agree, Master Issho can be a bit much.
But wouldn't you say
that Kaisei's promotion turned out okay?
CHOCHO KONJAKUTEI
He's young, but he's capable,
and has drawing power, after all.
But...
his promotion was,
by most standards, too premature.
A lot of people
are still grumbling about it.
Well, what do you expect?
Nothing irritates people more than
the sight of someone else
getting preferential treatment.
URARA RANSAIKA
If it irritates you, then all
you have to do is act just like Arakawa.
You can only be arrogant if you're
talented enough to get away with it.
Surely, people don't follow
the rules because
they're unable to assert themselves.
ENSO SANMEITEI
With all due respect, sir...
All right, that's enough.
Shomei, take a seat now.
The reason we,
the Rakugo Federation, exists
is to revitalize the Rakugo industry.
So let's enjoy ourselves doing that.
MIROKU KASHIWAYA
That being said,
I do understand how you all feel.
Maybe your people
are getting a bit too carried away.
Don't you think so, Arakawa?
Now, now, wake up!
Jugemu Jugemu Goko-no-surikirezu
Kaijari-suigyo no Suigyo-matsu
Ungyo-matsu Furai-matsu
Kuu-neru tokoro ni Sumu tokoro
Yaburakoji no Burakoji
Paipo-Paipo-Paipo no
Shuringan Shuringan no--
Ma'am!
I'm going to be late for school,
so I'll go on ahead!
Well, well! This is magnificent! Truly!
A student of ours making her mark
in the traditional arts.
And winning, no less!
You sure did a great job.
Really, you're at the top of the top.
The pinnacle!
Keep pushing onward
to the Eiger North Face!
Onward, onward!
- Oh, thank you very much!
- Onward!
Oh, pardon me!
Mountain climbing is my hobby, see.
All right, let's get one
made for you right away.
We need to celebrate, after all!
You know? That!
That?
CONGRATULATIONS STUDENT RAKUGO COMPETITION
KARAKU CUP WINNER! MS. AKANE OSAKI
By that, you mean this?
Oh, wow! Your name is huge!
It's Insta-worthy.
Come on! Strike a pose, Akane!
Great smile!
YEAR 3, CLASS 2
Hey, Osaki, how long
have you been doing Rakugo?
Um, well, for a pretty long time.
- Do you have, like, a partner?
- No, it's not stand-up.
Will you compete
in the comedy tournaments?
Nope, not doing that.
If you're on TV,
get me an idol singer's autograph!
Uh, no, that's not happening, okay?
Hey, come on, just let me get a photo!
Please?
- Sorry! I'm serious, I can't do that!
- Aww.
Hey, there she is!
- What do you mean?
- Osaki-senpai,
- can we get a selfie with you?
- Nope! Not happening! No way!
Hey, I wonder where she ran off to?
Over there, maybe?
- That way?
- Yeah.
Hey, she's not here.
Ms. Osaki?
LANGUAGE ARTS CENTER
Well, that sounds like a hassle.
But isn't Rakugo all about popularity?
I don't think it's a bad thing
to draw a lot of attention.
Well, sure, I totally appreciate it.
But it's happening so fast.
Your victory in the Karaku Cup is
something that you worked hard to achieve.
I think you can hold your head up high.
What, so you were running away
during lunch recess?
That's hilarious!
It's not funny.
I might have to skip school for a while.
- Still, how crazy is this?
- What?
I knew you were planning
to become a Rakugoka,
but now I know how hard
you've been training and all.
- Isn't that amazing?
- Amazing.
My training hasn't even begun yet.
Actually, it'll probably continue
for the rest of my life.
There are tons of people
who've been at it for over 50 years.
Whoa, 50 years? Unbelievable.
So you see,
I've got such a long way to go.
Hey, don't talk like that!
I mean, I'm using this
to convince my parents, you know.
Convince them?
Right. I've made up my mind.
Instead of junior college,
I'm gonna try to get in a trade school.
I'm seriously going to pursue a career
as a hair and makeup artist!
Huh? For real?
I'm not about to lose to you, Akane!
Right, Yuka?
Huh? Yuka, you're taking the entrance exam
for Shuei University, right?
Yes. But while I study for that exam,
I'm going to keep on studying art.
Goal. To make my debut
as an illustrator when I get into college.
- Wow, both of you are on fire!
- Well, yeah.
How can we not get motivated
after seeing this?
I'll bet there are others.
People who got some courage from you.
Is that right?
I know it's obvious,
but once we graduate, we're all
going off on our respective paths.
Yeah.
Hey, so we've only got six months left
to be high school girls!
That went by so fast.
Nope, we're not done yet!
We're going to enjoy
the last six months to the max!
Yeah!
You said that you wanted to take part
in practice at the university, right?
Didn't you just finish competing
in the interscholastic meet?
Yes, that's right.
But I only made it to the quarterfinals.
So I thought, "I don't want to lose."
That's a great attitude to have!
I'll set it up for you.
Make sure you don't let your studies
fall by the wayside, all right?
Yes, sir! Thank you for your support, sir!
Right.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, no, I really don't mind at all.
I'm so ashamed.
To commit such a blunder
when I'm your elder fellow apprentice!
Seriously, it's all good.
And thanks to that,
I realized what I was lacking.
Ani-san.
Please show me how to play the taiko,
and how to dance!
Wait, why are you looking at me like that?
Well, both Koguma Ani-san
and Guriko said to me...
"Akane will be after you
to teach her taiko and dance, for sure!"
They were so spot-on
that I couldn't help it.
Cringe!
That's the spirit!
But don't get greedy.
We'll start with taiko.
What I'm about to play
is the Ichiban-daiko that you hear
when the entertainment hall opens.
Hey, it's Dad!
I don't know. I'm just worried, I guess?
Worried?
What do you mean by that?
COIN LAUNDRY TSUZUKI
Well, see, you know what I mean.
They're just not open about it,
but because of how Master Issho
behaves and acts,
there are more than a few Rakugoka
who don't take kindly to "Arakawa."
And now, with that going on,
this article comes out.
Master Issho might be using
this competition
to produce the next Kaisei Arakawa.
That's a hot topic
even at our school, you know.
The hands that strike this taiko
are calling out to the audience
to keep coming, more and more.
Give it a try.
Right!
That article about the Karaku Cup...
It's getting a lot of buzz, huh?
Ani-san, you can see
online articles, then?
Don't ever underestimate a flip phone!
Well, they hung a banner at school, and
all these people come up to talk to me.
It makes me feel like
a celebrity or something.
And I'm not sure how I feel about that.
I'm glad that it makes them happy,
but still...
You can't say that I blew him away.
This is just me guessing...
But all those negative feelings
towards Master Issho...
might be turned to Akane now.
If it seemed like it had gone to her head,
I knew I'd have to set her straight.
but my fears were unfounded.
She'll start her official training
six months from now.
The Zenza training
might be grueling for her.
But if anyone,
my younger fellow apprentice can...
123RD RYOKUGYOKU HIGH SCHOOL
GRADUATION
- Shota Ehara.
- Yes, ma'am!
- Akane Osaki.
Congratulations.
GRADUATION CERTIFICATE
Hey, Master! Where are you going?
I'm going for a walk.
Compared to soba,
udon seems a little heavier.
Express the weight of it.
Well? Is that tasty?
Yes.
The syrup's dripping.
I'm fine.
Here, give it to me.
I'll fix it so it doesn't drip.
Nope.
- Come on, get in the picture.
- But...
This way, this way!
Akane.
I'm home.
Jugemu Jugemu...
Goko-no-surikirezu...
Hello!
Hello! It's the liquor store!
Hello?
I have a delivery for you.
Hey there!
Whoa! M-Master, you're answering the door?
Well, the thing is,
nobody's around this morning.
Oh, is that right?
So, what've you got?
Oh, this is it.
- Here you go.
- Right.
Thanks for your business!
Good work!
Oh, good work!
Hey! Akane! Thanks!
Good morning!
Morning.
Wanna crack one open?
You little fool.
Bring me some tea.
Right!
First, congratulations on graduating.
Thank you very much.
Just as I promised,
I'm granting you permission
to officially become my apprentice.
Thank you very much.
Going from trainee to Zenza means you'll
be working at the entertainment halls.
- Right.
- Give it all you've got.
I'll do my best!
And one more thing.
About your stage name...
- Master!
- Hm?
I can't tell you how grateful I am
to receive my name from you!
But my goal is to make Issho Arakawa
acknowledge Dad's Rakugo,
and to become a Shin'uchi.
I believe I can only become a full-fledged
Rakugoka when I've avenged my dad.
And so, once I've become a Shin'uchi,
that's when I'd like to revisit this and
receive my name from you as a Rakugoka.
Please, if you could please humor me.
I know that as your apprentice,
I'm out of line, talking this way!
But until I become a Shin'uchi...
Please, let me keep the name Akane.
ARAKAWA
AKANE
That's what I thought you'd say.
Master.
The day you become a Shin'uchi,
I'll give you the best name ever.
If you don't make it,
then that'll be that.
Does that sound good?
Yes!
CONGRATULATIONS
GRADUATION & APPRENTICESHIP
Celebrate, celebrate!
Celebrate graduation!
Celebrate apprenticeship!
All right, Akane,
let's hear your Ichiban-daiko!
You got it!
All right!
ZENZA TRAINING BEGINS
Akane Small Talk!
I'm so thrilled
to receive my theater name!
Right. This one was a struggle for me,
but I'm glad that it's settled now.
From here on in, work hard as a Zenza.
Right! Um, you said it was a struggle.
Does that mean there were
other names you had in mind?
Well, I guess you could say that.
Really? I want to know!
What kind of names?
Don't ask foolish questions.
Well, there were all kinds.
One of the most typical ways
is to come up with a name containing
one character from the master's name.
Your name?
I took the "shi" from "Shiguma"
for "Shinta,"
and the "guma" from "Shiguma"
for "Koguma."
Oh, I see.
You need to apply yourself,
so that one day,
when you become a Shin'uchi,
you'll be able to live up to a fine name.
Aka. Huh? Aka...
Hm? What's eating you?
Oh, actually, I was wondering
what kind of name I'd give,
if I ever took on an apprentice.
I'd take the "Aka" from "Akane" and...
Um, "Aka-tombo"?
"Account"?
"Main Account"? "Other Account"?
"Shadow Account"?
You little fool!
You're going about it all wrong!
That's "Akarasama"!
Meaning, "clear as day"!